Burlesque is a drama film directed by Dominic Deacon.
Frank Bannister is about to have a very long night.
A writer of violent horror stories, Frank is alone,
depressed and one step from full blown alcoholism.
Late one dark and stormy night his quiet hermit existence is disturbed
when two eccentric exotic dancers arrive on his doorstep.
Alternatively seductive and sinister the beautiful women
promise to make all Frank's dreams come true.
They prove to be as good as their word.
Only problem is, Frank is a man with very dark dreams indeed.
Frank Bannister, played by Haydn Evans.
Veronica, played by Christina Hallett.
Tammy, played by Poppy Cherry.
Fiona, played by Virginia Bowers.
Richard, played by Dennis Kreusler.
Burlesque is a 2010 American backstage musical film
written and directed by Steven Antin.
It stars Cher, Christina Aguilera in her film debut, Kristen Bell, Cam Gigandet, Stanley Tucci, Julianne
Hough, Alan Cumming, and Peter Gallagher, and features cameos from Dianna Agron and James Brolin.
The film tells the story of Ali (Aguilera), an aspiring singer who leaves her small hometown for Los
Angeles, where she becomes a dancer at a struggling burlesque lounge owned by Tess (Cher).
After a performance is sabotaged by her rival, Nikki (Bell), Ali sings the song herself,
impressing Tess and leading to her becoming the main attraction of the lounge.
Burlesque marks Aguilera's first leading role, as well as Cher's first
musical performance on screen since 1967's Good Times.
Filming for Burlesque took place in California from November 2009 to March 2010.
It was released in the United States on November 24, 2010, by Screen Gems.
Its jazz-inspired soundtrack was released ahead of the film's release
on November 19, 2010, by RCA Records and Screen Gems.
Aguilera and Cher both contributed to the album.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the cast's
performance and the soundtrack but criticized the writing.
Burlesque did modestly at the box office, grossing $91 million worldwide and
earning an additional $42 million in domestic video sales.
The film was nominated for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy at the 68th Golden Globe Awards, where Cher's
performance of "You Haven't Seen the Last of Me", written by Diane Warren, won for Best Original Song.
The soundtrack was nominated for Best Compilation Soundtrack
for Visual Media in the 54th Grammy Awards.
A stage musical adaptation of the film premiered in June 2024.
The tone is dark and emotional.